decipherinc.com 2013-08-06

# Privacy Policy | Decipher

###  1\. Introduction

**1.1. Purpose of Policy.** Decipher, Inc. (the “Company”) is committed to respecting the privacy rights of its clients, visitors, and other users of the Company’s Website (the “Site”). The Company created this Website Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) to give you confidence as you visit and use the Site, and to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. This Policy is only applicable to the Site, and not to any other websites that you may be able to access from the Site, each of which may have data collection and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Policy.

**1.2. Notice Concerning Children.** The services offered by the Company include on-line surveys. Some of the surveys provided by the Company are directed at children under the age of 13. In connection with these surveys, all survey respondents who are minors are provided by third party sample providers who are required to certify to the Company their compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). Of course, we understand and are committed to respecting the sensitive nature of children’s privacy online. As a result, at any time, a parent of a minor who has responded to any survey hosted on this website may contact the Company at the address noted below and request that we (i) disclose to the parent any personal information maintained in connection with their child, (ii) delete from our system any personal information maintained in connection with their child, or (iii) refuse to allow any further collection or use of their child’s personal information.

###  2\. Information Collection Practices

**2.1. What Basic Information Does the Company Collect?**  
The Site includes a number of features, including, free webinar sign-ups, job inquiries and quote requests, that ask users to provide certain personal information, including, their names, e-mail addresses, and other contact information. The Company also collects certain survey data from individuals who voluntary reply to surveys hosted by the Company.

**2.2. What Additional Information Does Company Collect?**  
(a) Automatic Collection. Our servers automatically recognize visitors’ domain names and IP addresses (the number assigned to computers on the Internet). No personal information about you is revealed in this process. The Site may also gather anonymous “traffic data” that does not personally identify you, but that may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer.

(b) Cookies. From time to time, we may use the standard “cookies” feature of major browser applications that allows us to store a small piece of data on your computer about your visit to our Web site. We do not set any personally identifiable information in cookies, nor do we employ any data capture mechanisms on our website other than cookies. Cookies help us learn which areas of our site are useful and which areas need improvement. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser. However, if you choose to disable this function, your experience at our Web site may be diminished and some features may not work as they were intended.

###  3\. Use and Sharing of Information

**3.1. What Does the Company do With Collected Information?**  
(a) Personal Information. We will not share your personal information with any third parties without your consent, except as necessary to provide you with the services offered by us or to comply with the law. We may also use your contact information to inform you of any changes to the Site, or to send you additional information about Company. The Company’s policy is to use personal information only in ways that are compatible with the purpose for which it was collected, including survey data collection and reporting.

(b) Anonymous Information. We use anonymous information to analyze our Site traffic, but we do not examine this information for individually identifying information. In addition, we may use anonymous IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, or to display the content according to your preferences.

(c) Disclosure Personal Information. We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Company or its parent company, subsidiaries or affiliates, (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Company or the users of the Site, or (3) act under exigent circumstances to protect the safety of the public or users of the Site.

(d) E-Mail Contents. We will not disclose to third parties private e-mail communications that are sent or received as part of using our services, except as reasonably required to operate the service or as otherwise authorized by law.

(e) Access to Information. The Company will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor any requests to change the information that we collect about you, such as name, contact information and passwords. The Company will also use commercially reasonable efforts to remove all information about you from our database if you make such a request by contacting us in accordance with Section 7.1 below.

**3.2 Spam Prevention**  
The Company uses a service called [Mollom](http://www.mollom.com/) to protect against spam on our public forms. By submitting a comment, newsletter request, or contact request, you agree to Mollom's [privacy policy](http://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy).

###  4\. Security

The Site has commercially reasonable security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that we obtain from you, and the Company continues to explore ways to enhance these security measures. However, the Company makes no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse, to you or to any third party arising out of any such loss, misuse, or alteration.

###  5\. Safe Harbor Principles

As a result of the Company’s business within the European Union (“EU”), the Company strives to comply with EU law concerning data protection and privacy. In this regard, the Company adheres to the Safe Harbor Principles adopted and approved by the United Sates Department of Commerce for compliance with the EU’s privacy legislation, including the Directive on Data Protection. In accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles, in addition to the other provisions set forth in this privacy policy, the following shall apply in connection with any personal information collected in the EU:

(a) Notice and Choice. The Company may collect personal information directly from individuals in the EU, as part of conducting surveys for the Company's clients. This information is freely given by survey respondents and as far as is reasonably practicable, the information remains anonymous when it is reported. To the extent permitted by the Safe Harbor Principles, we reserve the right to process any personal information that may exist in the survey responses in the course of providing survey data collection and hosting services to our clients with or without the knowledge of the individuals involved.

(b) Onward Transfers. The Company will not knowingly disclose an individual's personal information to third parties, except when one or more of the following conditions is true: (i) we have the individual's permission to make the disclosure; (ii) the disclosure is required by law or professional standards; (iii) the information in question is publicly available; or (iv) the disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or defense of legal claims.

(c) Dispute Resolution. If you have any complaint concerning how the Company has handled your personal information, please contact the Company immediately and the Company will make every reasonable effort to address and resolve your concerns.  In the event that the Company is unable to resolve your concerns, the Company has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by the Company, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint.

###  6\. Enforcement

The Company utilizes the self-assessment approach to assure its compliance with our privacy policy. The Company periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and in conformity with the Safe Harbor Principles.

###  7\. Contact Information and Policy Updates

**7.1. Contacting Us.**

If you have any questions about this Policy, our practices related to this Site, or if you would like to have us remove your information from our database please feel contact us at the following address:

**Decipher, Inc.**  
7 River Park Place, Suite 110  
Fresno, California 93720  
559-436-6940  
www.decipherinc.com

**7.2. Updates and Changes.**  
We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Policy, simply by posting such change, update, or modification on the Site and without any other notice to you. Any such change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. It is your responsibility to review this Policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms.﻿
